# Pierrick KINIF

pierrick-kinif@hotmail.be



in linkedin.com/in/pierrickkinif



https://www.pierrickkinif.com/

## Summary

MBA graduate, Ex-Credit Risk Data Analyst, Ex-Assistant Sustainability Practice, I am currently working as a Department Manager at Decathlon. I have found that nothing satisfies me more than evolving in a dynamic, intellectual, and challenging environment which places people and planet at the heart of all of its decision-making. I am a goal-oriented person and my passion for data science (R user [2+ years]) helps me to develop excellent decision-making tools and techniques based on tangible information.

# **Experience**



## **Hiking Department Manager**

Apr 2019- Present

**Decathlon Belgium** 



#### Ski Department Manager

Sep 2018 - Mar 2019

**Decathlon Belgium** Decathlon's main mission is to make sport accessible to the many!

# Leading a team of 10-15 individuals who are fanatically devoted to sharing their sport passion

- # Implement a strategy to increase sales growth (+ 8%)
- # Support, challenge and build both commercial and human skills of the team
- # Ensure and improve customer satisfaction



#### **Assistant, Sustainability Practice**

Sep 2017 - Mar 2018

Inspiring More Sustainability

7 months

7 months

Luxemburgish network that accompanies organizations in their commitment to CSR by enhancing dialogue with their stakeholders.

- # Results analysis of a CSR survey for presentation during the Luxembourg Sustainability Forum (i.e. LSF) 2017 and later publication.
- # Help for the organization of the LSF2017 + media follow-up
- # Organization of a workshop in the context of the Food pillar of the "Third Industrial Revolution"
- # Measurement of the company's carbon footprint
- # Research and writing assistance for the publication of the magazine "Sustainability MAG"



#### Credit Risk Data Analyst Intern

Jan 2017 - Jun 2017

Banque Internationale à Luxembourg (BIL)

6 months

The oldest private banking group in the Grand Duchy and among the country's top three banks.

- # Using SQL for validating and ensuring consistency of the credit risk databases
- # Development of a VBA application to automatize the data validation process
- # Review risk exposure calculations and forecasts for Basel requirements



Campus Consultant

Sep 2015 - Mar 2016

4UCAMPUS - READ MORE, PAY LESS

7 months

A company which offers reductions on newspapers, magazines, computers, software, and printers to students and academic staff.

- # Sales of subscriptions of press titles to students and academic staff
- # Promote the company's products
- # Expand the client base



## **Consulting Project**

Sep 2015 - Jan 2016

Lunch Garden 5 months

Belgian fast food chain of more than 70 restaurants.

# Improve the employer branding of the company



#### Student Job

Sep 2012 - Dec 2015

Horeca 3 years 4 months

Barman and Server at Les Caves à Bières, the Piano bar, and the Arsenal Namur.

# Financing my studies

#### **Education**



#### **University of Luxembourg**

2017 - 2018

Certificate in Sustainable Development and Social Innovation, Sustainability Studies



#### Université de Namur

2015 - 2018

Master's Degree, Business Administration and Management, General, Distinction

Thesis: "Towards Green Companies: A Panel Data Study of The Environmental and Financial Performance Nexus".

# This master's thesis has been written in R Markdown to make it transparent and reproducible for the reader.

# All resources are available on my GitHub account and can be gladly shared upon request.



# School of Economics, Business and Accounting at the University of São Paulo

2016 - 2017

Master's Degree, Finance, General, Great Distinction



#### Université de Namur

2012 - 2015

Bachelor's Degree, Business Administration and Management, General



#### **College Saint Joseph - Chimay**

2007 - 2012

High School, General Studies, Certificat d'Enseignement Secondaire Supérieur (CESS)

#### **Certifications**

## Data Analyst with R Track • DataCamp

Jun 2018 - Present

#### Importing & Cleaning Data with R Track • DataCamp

Aug 2018 - Present

#### R Programming Track • DataCamp

Apr 2019 - Present